Listen to a teacher talking in a social studies class.
Have you ever thought about the games that people played hundreds of years ago?
In the Middle Ages, people often got together and competed in various folk games.
They would form teams and kick around a ball or some round object.
The objective of a folk game was most often to move the ball to some fixed point and score points.
Sounds a lot like modem games, doesn’t it?
But in actuality, folk games were much different !
One big difference is that nowadays the rules of such games are written down.
Each game has a specific clear set of rules that you can look up
and consult when you’re not sure what to do.
In the past, though, very few people who played these games could even read.
So they simply memorized the rules and passed them down by tradition.
Also, the teams that played in folk games were nothing like the carefully structured
teams in today’s games.
Today，each player has a specific role.Like in soccer,
when one player’s job is to protect the goal,
and others try to score.
There's a lot of specialization in roles and positions.
But in the past, folk games were played more like children play games today.
Think about how kids usually play a game:
they will often change positions or roles.
This is more or less how teams were organized in the past.And another difference,
nowadays, sports games are considered very positive activities.
They keep you healthy and they teach teamwork.But folk games of the past were not regarded so positively.
They were often played in the streets,
and to a lot of people, they looked more like scary riots than sport events!
The games were very rowdy and often ended in broken windows
or other damage to property.
In fact, folk games were considered so primitive that authorities in some places even
tried to ban them completely.
For example, in medieval England, authorities tried up to 30 times to stop such
contests from being organized.
But it didn't work.
People continued to play these games in the streets for hundreds of years.